

# Alex Woodman Full Stack Developer, UX Enthusiast alexthegoodman.com alexthegoodman@gmail.com 616.325.5407

### **Summary**

# I am passionate about user experience and the development that brings it to life

Since I was just a boy in elementary school, I've been creating interfaces. Nowadays, I serve clients on the web and on mobile to overcome business obstacles and satisfy target segments.

#### Qualifications

- Semantic Markup
  - SASS / CSS processors

Grand Rapids, MI

- FE JavaScript ES7+ (jQuery, React, React Native, Gulp, TypeScript, Angular, AngularJS)
- BE JavaScript (Node, Express, SSR, Babel, Webpack, NPM, Yarn, CRUD, logging, error handling, style guides)
- BE PHP (WordPress Plugins, Craft Plugins)
- Custom CMS (Craft CMS, ExpressionEngine, WordPress)
- New Technologies (Variable Fonts, CSS Grid, LoopBack 4, etc)
- DevOps, QA Processes, GIT, Pipelines, CI / CD, Automated Unit, Integrated, and UI Testing
- Development Tools (VS Code, WebStorm, Terminal, XCode)
- Collaboration Tools (Atlassian Suite, Github, GitLab, Asana, Trello, Slack)
- Design Tools (Sketch, Photoshop, Illustrator, InVision)
- Infrastructure Tools (Heroku, AWS S3 and RDS)

## Featured Work

Websites, ranging from front-end pixel-perfection and performance to CMS integration, custom add-on development, and API integration.

#### **American Seating**

www.americanseating.com

#### **Brains Potential**

brainspotential.com

#### **Baumann Building**

baumannbuilding.com

#### **Ammie Bouwman**

ammiebouwman.com

#### Reeviewr

reeviewr.com

Web and Mobile Applications, ranging from animated buttons and progressive on-boarding processes to versioned, optimized APIs.

#### **Assets Beta**

assetsbeta.com

#### WebLeap

An app that allowed the user to control their browser through hand gestures in the air.

## **Experience**

#### Freelance Web Developer

January 2013 to Now

Identify and obtain all business information related to the challenge at hand

Develop specifications and requirements for projects

Implement verifiable quality assurance controls

Deliver projects which meet or exceed scope requirements

Provide long-term support mechanisms and procedures

#### **EDUStaff**

March 2018 to Now

Collaborate closely with other developers throughout planning, deliberation, and production stages

Develop front-end features according to best-practices

Develop unit tests intended for CI pipelines and deployment systems Employ new Web APIs, browser features, syntax optimizations and standardization

#### Cull Group

October 2015 to June 2016

Translate Photoshop and Sketch designs and wireframes to standardscompliant, mobile-responsive, backwards-compatible pages Integrate pages with ExpressionEngine CMS and enable control of content pieces, meta data and other items

Develop email newsletters and transactional email notifications which work through a variety of email clients (including Outlook) and integrate with the CMS Enjoyed the chance to experiment with a Canvas-based Bejeweled-style game for mobile devices

#### **Thinkbox Creative**

February 2014 to January 2015

Collaborate closely with designers and project managers to ensure timely completion of all deliverables

Translate Photoshop designs to standards-compliant, mobile-responsive, backwards-compatible pages

Integrate pages with WordPress CMS and enable control of content pieces, layout, meta data and other items

#### Givinci

July 2013 to December 2013

Collaborate with various stakeholders (from management to marketing) to aid in designing pages

Develop pages and modules using in-house development techniques Gained valuable experience with Ruby on Rails PostgreSQL, and other technologies Acquired insights into start-up planning and coordination

#### Education

#### Self-Taught

January 2010 to Now

Read and study targeted books
Engage with community
Stay involved with news and industry trends
Build projects which demonstrate standards